<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Self-Hosting on Prajwol Bikram Adhikari</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/self-hosting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self-Hosting on Prajwol Bikram Adhikari</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/self-hosting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: Reviving an Old Laptop with Debian &amp; Docker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/homelab-series-part-1-debian-docker-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/homelab-series-part-1-debian-docker-foundation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the first post in my new homelab series! I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fascinated by self-hosting and DevOps, and I believe the best way to learn is by doing. In this series, I&amp;rsquo;ll document my journey of turning an old, unused laptop into a powerful, efficient, and secure bare-metal server for hosting a variety of network services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal for this first part is to lay a solid foundation. We&amp;rsquo;ll take an old laptop, install a minimal and stable Linux operating system, perform some initial security hardening, and set up Docker as our containerization engine. By the end of this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll have a perfect blank canvas ready for the exciting services we&amp;rsquo;ll deploy in the upcoming parts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Private Adguard Server on Cloud (Linode)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/adguard-home-on-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/adguard-home-on-cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-the-buzz-about-adguard-home&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the buzz about AdGuard Home?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine AdGuard Home as your personal internet guardian. This versatile tool blocks ads, trackers, and other online nuisances across all devices connected to your network. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re browsing on your phone, tablet, or computer, AdGuard Home has your back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s digital landscape, robust security measures are paramount. Protecting each device shields your family from accidental clicks and malicious attacks, ensuring peace of mind and a secure online environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
