<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>DNS on Prajwol Bikram Adhikari</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/dns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DNS on Prajwol Bikram Adhikari</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/dns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Part 3: A High-Availability DNS Network with AdGuard Home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/homelab-series-part-3-high-availability-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/homelab-series-part-3-high-availability-dns/</guid>
      <description>How I built a high-availability DNS setup using AdGuard Home, Oracle Cloud, and upstream resolvers like Cloudflare, Google, and Quad9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Built My Own Ad-Blocking DNS Server in the Cloud (2025 Updated Edition!)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/adguard-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/adguard-updated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;your-personal-internet-guardian-how-to-build-a-free-ad-blocker-in-the-cloud-&#34;&gt;Your Personal Internet Guardian: How to Build a FREE Ad-Blocker in the Cloud! 🚀&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! A while back, I wrote a guide on setting up AdGuard Home on Linode. The world of tech moves fast, and it&amp;rsquo;s time for an upgrade! Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to build our own powerful, network-wide ad-blocker using &lt;strong&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS)&lt;/strong&gt;, and we&amp;rsquo;ll make it secure with our own domain and SSL certificate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of this as building a digital gatekeeper for your internet. Before any ads, trackers, or malicious sites can reach your devices, our AdGuard Home server will slam the door shut. The best part? This works on your phone, laptop, smart TV—anything on your network—without installing a single app on them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Private Adguard Server on Cloud (Linode)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/adguard-home-on-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/adguard-home-on-cloud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-the-buzz-about-adguard-home&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the buzz about AdGuard Home?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine AdGuard Home as your personal internet guardian. This versatile tool blocks ads, trackers, and other online nuisances across all devices connected to your network. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re browsing on your phone, tablet, or computer, AdGuard Home has your back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s digital landscape, robust security measures are paramount. Protecting each device shields your family from accidental clicks and malicious attacks, ensuring peace of mind and a secure online environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT Support Specialist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/experience/islingtoncollege/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/experience/islingtoncollege/</guid>
      <description>Islington College | Kathmandu, Nepal</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
